http://www.nmt.edu/privacy/index.php

Skip to main content
Interim Privacy Policy
New Mexico Tech maintains its web sites as an information resource and service for
the public and this privacy policy applies to all pages of this site that are maintained
by New Mexico Tech (https://www.nmt.edu) Our policy is to collect no personal information about you when you visit our website
unless you choose to make such information available to us.
Personally Identifiable Information
If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains
personally identifying information, or fill out a form that provides us this information,
we will only use the personally-identifiable information to respond to your request
and analyze trends. We may redirect your message to another person who is in a better
position to answer your question. Some departments include forms to be submitted in
regard to acceptance into the school or their individual program and are reviewed
by admittance committees. In regard to filling out forms, you will be given a chance
to "opt out" of completing the form.
Google Analytics
New Mexico Tech uses Google Analytics to track and analyze internet visitor usage
data, which may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type, internet
service provider, the pages and files viewed on our site, operating system, length
of visit, access times, referring website addresses, and web browser cookies. The
information collected provides New Mexico Tech staff the ability to see which pages
are most viewed and some aggregated data about users. This data is controlled under
Google’s privacy policy; full text is available here: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ .
This non-personalized information is used to monitor site effectiveness and possible
areas of improvement and is stored on Google’s servers.
We additionally gather information regarding the volume and timing of access by collecting
information on the date, time, and website pages accessed by visitors to https://www.nmt.edu. We collect this information to improve the content of our website, and no individual
information is collected.
Google Analytics is an industry standard. If for some reason you would like to limit
the data shared with Google, it is suggested to use a private browsing window without
being logged into any Google services. At the end of your session you should close
the window. This will limit the information collected to only include your nmt.edu
browsing behavior.
Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics terms of
use and Google's privacy practices. To opt out of Google’s data collection, read more
about the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on.
Online Surveys
New Mexico Tech is a research institution. At any time, there are many online surveys
being conducted. Unless otherwise noted on the specified survey, your answers are
confidential and individual responses will not be shared with other parties unless
required by the New Mexico Inspection of Public Records Act. Aggregate data from surveys
may be shared with external third parties.
Links to External Websites
Webpages for New Mexico Tech and its academic and administrative departments may contain
links to other websites. Outgoing links from New Mexico Tech webpages in no way implies
authorization or endorsement of that site by New Mexico Tech, its leadership, or the
New Mexico Tech Board of Regents. New Mexico Tech is not responsible for the content
of these outside websites, or for their individual privacy policies. Readers are advised
to carefully read and consider each website’s privacy policy before disclosing any
personal information.
Social Media Policy
New Mexico Tech maintains social media accounts on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube,
and SnapChat. By following these accounts information may be collected by each social
media company. Data collected by your use of these services is managed under those
sites privacy policies.
Concerns or Changes
New Mexico Tech may change this privacy policy at any time by posting revisions to
this website. Your use of this website constitutes acceptance of the provisions of
this privacy policy and your continued usage after such changes are posted constitutes
acceptance of each revised policy.
Please check https://www.nmt.edu/privacy periodically for changes. If you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy
or any revised privacy policy, please leave this website immediately.
The authoritative source on this policy and responsibility for its implementation
rests with the NMT Chief Information Officer.
FERPA and HIPAA Policies
NMT FERPA Policy
NMT HIPAA Policy
©
